<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 C:\grobid-0.5.1\grobid-0.5.1\grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-11-08T05:34+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Sequential Short-Text Classification with Recurrent and Convolutional Neural Networks</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2016-03-12">12 Mar 2016</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ji</forename><forename type="middle">Young</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
							<email>jjylee@mit.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">MIT</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">MIT</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Franck</forename><surname>Dernoncourt</surname></persName>
							<email>francky@mit.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">MIT</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">MIT</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Sequential Short-Text Classification with Recurrent and Convolutional Neural Networks</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2016-03-12">12 Mar 2016</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>Accepted as a conference paper at NAACL 2016</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Recent approaches based on artificial neural networks (ANNs) have shown promising results for short-text classification. However, many short texts occur in sequences (e.g., sentences in a document or utterances in a dialog), and most existing ANN-based systems do not leverage the preceding short texts when classifying a subsequent one. In this work, we present a model based on recurrent neural networks and convolutional neural networks that incorporates the preceding short texts. Our model achieves state-of-the-art results on three different datasets for dialog act prediction .</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Short-text classification is an important task in many areas of natural language processing, includ- ing sentiment analysis, question answering, or dia- log management. Many different approaches have been developed for short-text classification, such as using Support Vector Machines (SVMs) with rule-based features <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Silva et al., 2011</ref>), combin- ing SVMs with naive Bayes ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Wang and Manning, 2012)</ref>, and building dependency trees with Con- ditional Random Fields ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Nakagawa et al., 2010)</ref>. Several recent studies using ANNs have shown promising results, including convolutional neural networks (CNNs) <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Kim, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Blunsom et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Kalchbrenner et al., 2014</ref>) and recursive neural net- works ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Socher et al., 2012</ref>).</p><p>Most ANN systems classify short texts in isola- tion, i.e., without considering preceding short texts.</p><p>However, short texts usually appear in sequence (e.g., sentences in a document or utterances in a di- alog), therefore using information from preceding short texts may improve the classification accuracy. Previous works on sequential short-text classifica- tion are mostly based on non-ANN approaches, such as Hidden Markov Models (HMMs) <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Reithinger and Klesen, 1997)</ref>, ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Stolcke et al., 2000</ref>), maximum en- tropy ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Ang et al., 2005</ref>), and naive Bayes ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Lendvai and Geertzen, 2007)</ref>.</p><p>Inspired by the performance of ANN-based sys- tems for non-sequential short-text classification, we introduce a model based on recurrent neural net- works (RNNs) and CNNs for sequential short-text classification, and evaluate it on the dialog act classi- fication task. A dialog act characterizes an utterance in a dialog based on a combination of pragmatic, se- mantic, and syntactic criteria. Its accurate detection is useful for a range of applications, from speech recognition to automatic summarization ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Stolcke et al., 2000</ref>). Our model achieves state-of-the-art re- sults on three different datasets.</p><p>2 Model * These authors contributed equally to this work.</p><p>Our model comprises two parts. The first part gener- ates a vector representation for each short text using either the RNN or CNN architecture, as discussed in Section 2.1 and <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>. The second part classifies the current short text based on the vector representa- tions of the current as well as a few preceding short texts, as presented in Section 2.2 and <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref>.</p><p>We denote scalars with italic lowercases (e.g., k, b f ), vectors with bold lowercases (e.g., s, x i ), and matrices with italic uppercases (e.g., W f ). We   use the colon notation v i:j to denote the sequence of vectors (v i , v i+1 , . . . , v j ).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Short-text representation</head><p>A given short text of length is represented as the se- quence of m-dimensional word vectors x 1: , which is used by the RNN or CNN model to produce the n-dimensional short-text representation s.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.1">RNN-based short-text representation</head><p>The symbols σ(·) and tanh(·) refer to the element- wise sigmoid and hyperbolic tangent functions, and is the element-wise multiplication. h 0 = c 0 = 0.</p><p>In the pooling layer, the sequence of vectors h 1: output from the RNN layer are combined into a sin- gle vector s ∈ R n that represents the short-text, us- ing one of the following mechanisms: last, mean, and max pooling. Last pooling takes the last vector, i.e., s = h , mean pooling averages all vectors, i.e., s =</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>1</head><p>We use a variant of RNN called Long Short Term Memory (LSTM) <ref type="bibr">(Hochreiter and Schmidhuber, 1997</ref>). For the t th word in the short-text, an LSTM takes as input x t , h t−1 , c t−1 and produces h t , c t based on the following formulas: t=1 h t , and max pooling takes the element- wise maximum of h 1: .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.2">CNN-based short-text representation</head><p>Using a filter W f ∈ R h×m of height h, a convolu- tion operation on h consecutive word vectors start- ing from t th word outputs the scalar feature</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">i t = σ(W i x t + U i h t−1 + b i ) f t = σ(W f x t + U f h t−1 + b f ) c t = ReLU(W f • X t:t+h−1 + b f ) ˜ c t = tanh(W c x t + U c h t−1 + b c ) c t = f t c t−1 + i t ˜ c t o t = σ(W o x t + U o h t−1 + b o ) h t = o t tanh(c t )</formula><p>where W j ∈ R n×m , U j ∈ R n×n are weight matri- ces and b j ∈ R n are bias vectors, for j ∈ {i, f, c, o}.</p><p>where X t:t+h−1 ∈ R h×m is the matrix whose i th row is x i ∈ R m , and b f ∈ R is a bias. The symbol • refers to the dot product and ReLU(·) is the element- wise rectified linear unit function.</p><p>We perform convolution operations with n dif- ferent filters, and denote the resulting features as c t ∈ R n , each of whose dimensions comes from a distinct filter. Repeating the convolution operations for each window of h consecutive words in the short- text, we obtain c 1: . The short-text representa- tion s ∈ R n is computed in the max pooling layer, as the element-wise maximum of c 1: .</p><p>For MRDA, we use the train/validation/test splits provided with the datasets. For DSTC 4 and SwDA, only the train/test splits are provided. <ref type="bibr">1</ref>  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Training</head><formula xml:id="formula_1">y j = tanh d 1 W −d s j−d + b 1 , ∀j ∈ [i − d 2 , i] d=0</formula><p>where W 0 , W −1 , W −2 ∈ R k×n are the weight ma- trices, b 1 ∈ R k is the bias vector, y j ∈ R k is the class representation, and k is the number of classes for the classification task. Similarly, the second layer takes as input the se- quence of class representations y i−d 2 :i and outputs</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">z i ∈ R k :</formula><p>The model is trained to minimize the negative log- likelihood of predicting the correct dialog acts of the utterances in the train set, using stochastic gradient descent with the Adadelta update rule <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Zeiler, 2012)</ref>. At each gradient descent step, weight matrices, bias vectors, and word vectors are updated. For regular- ization, dropout is applied after the pooling layer, and early stopping is used on the validation set with a patience of 10 epochs.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Results and Discussion</head><formula xml:id="formula_3"> d 2  z i = softmax  W −j y i−j + b 2  j=0</formula><p>To find effective hyperparameters, we varied one hy- perparameter at a time while keeping the other ones fixed. <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 2</ref> presents our hyperparameter choices.</p><p>where U 0 , U −1 , U −2 ∈ R k×k and b 2 ∈ R k are the weight matrices and bias vector.</p><p>The final output z i represents the probability dis- tribution over the set of k classes for the i th short- text: the j th element of z i corresponds to the proba- bility that the i th short-text belongs to the j th class. We evaluate our model on the dialog act classifica- tion task using the following datasets:</p><p>• DSTC 4: Dialog State Tracking Challenge 4 ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Kim et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Kim et al., 2016</ref>).</p><p>• MRDA: ICSI Meeting Recorder Dialog Act Cor- pus ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Janin et al., 2003;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Shriberg et al., 2004</ref>). The 5 classes are introduced in ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Ang et al., 2005</ref>).</p><p>• SwDA: Switchboard Dialog Act Corpus ( <ref type="bibr">Jurafsky et al., 1997</ref>). We initialized the word vectors with the 300- dimensional word vectors pretrained with word2vec on Google News ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Mikolov et al., 2013a;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Mikolov et al., 2013b</ref>) for DSTC 4, and the 200-dimensional  <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>: Accuracy (%) on different architectures and history sizes d1, d2. For each setting, we report average (minimum, maximum) computed on 5 runs. Sequential classification (d1 + d2 &gt; 0) outperforms non-sequential classification (d1 = d2 = 0). Overall, the CNN model outperformed the LSTM model for all datasets, albeit by a small margin except for SwDA. We also tried a variant of the LSTM model, gated recurrent units ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Cho et al., 2014</ref>), but the results were generally lower than LSTM.</p><p>word vectors pretrained with GloVe on Twit- ter ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Pennington et al., 2014</ref>) for MRDA and SwDA, as these choices yielded the best results among all publicly available word2vec, GloVe, SENNA <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Collobert, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Collobert et al., 2011</ref>) and RNNLM (Mikolov et al., 2011) word vectors. The effects of the history sizes d 1 and d 2 for the short-text and the class representations, respectively, are presented in <ref type="table">Table 3</ref> for both the LSTM and CNN models. In both models, increasing d 1 while keeping d 2 = 0 improved the performances by 1.3- 4.2 percentage points. Conversely, increasing d 2 while keeping d 1 = 0 yielded better results, but the performance increase was less pronounced: incor- porating sequential information at the short-text rep- resentation level was more effective than at the class representation level.</p><p>Using sequential information at both the short- text representation level and the class representa- tion level does not help in most cases and may even lower the performances. We hypothesize that short- text representations contain richer and more gen- eral information than class representations due to their larger dimension. Class representations may not convey any additional information over short- text representations, and are more likely to propa- gate errors from previous misclassifications. <ref type="table">Table 4</ref> compares our results with the state-of-the- art. Overall, our model shows competitive results, while requiring no human-engineered features. Rig- orous comparisons are challenging to draw, as many important details such as text preprocessing and train/valid/test split may vary, and many studies fail to perform several runs despite the randomness in some parts of the training process, such as weight initialization. Interlabeler agreement - - 84.0 <ref type="table">Table 4</ref>: Accuracy (%) of our models and other methods from the literature. The majority class model predicts the most fre- quent class. SVM: <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Dernoncourt et al., 2016)</ref>. Graphical model: <ref type="bibr">(Ji and Bilmes, 2006</ref>). Naive Bayes: <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Lendvai and Geertzen, 2007)</ref>. HMM: ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Stolcke et al., 2000</ref>). Memory-based Learning: <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Rotaru, 2002)</ref>. All five models use features derived from tran- scribed words, as well as previous predicted dialog acts except for Naive Bayes. The interlabeler agreement could be obtained only for SwDA. For the CNN and LSTM models, the presented results are the test set accuracy of the run with the highest accu- racy on the validation set.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusion</head><p>In this article we have presented an ANN-based ap- proach to sequential short-text classification. We demonstrate that adding sequential information im- proves the quality of the predictions, and the per- formance depends on what sequential information is used in the model. Our model achieves state-of-the- art results on three different datasets for dialog act prediction.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: RNN (left) and CNN (right) architectures for generating the vector representation s of a short text x 1:. For CNN, Conv refers to convolution operations, and the filter height h = 3 is used in this figure.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Four instances of the two-layer feedforward ANN used for predicting the probability distribution over the classes zi for the i th short-text Xi. S2V stands for short text to vector, which is the RNN/CNN architecture that generates si from Xi. From left to right, the history sizes (d1, d2) are (0, 0), (2, 0), (0, 2) and (1, 1). (0, 0) corresponds to the non-sequential classification case.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head>Table 1 presents statistics on the datasets.</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>2.2 Sequential short-text classification 

Dataset |C| |V | 
Train 
Validation 
Test 

Let s i be the n-dimensional short-text representation 
given by the RNN or CNN architecture for the i th 
short text in the sequence. The sequence s i−d 1 −d 2 : i 
is fed into a two-layer feedforward ANN that pre-
dicts the class for the i th short text. The hyperpa-
rameters d 1 , d 2 are the history sizes used in the first 
and second layers, respectively. 
The first layer takes as input s i−d 1 −d 2 : i and out-
puts the sequence y i−d 2 : i defined as 

DSTC 4 89 6k 
24 (21k) 
5 (5k) 
6 (6k) 

MRDA 
5 12k 
51 (78k) 
11 (16k) 11 (15k) 

SwDA 
43 20k 1003 (193k) 112 (23k) 19 (5k) 

Table 1: Dataset overview. |C| is the number of classes, |V | 
the vocabulary size. For the train, validation and test sets, we 
indicate the number of dialogs (i.e., sequences) followed by the 
number of utterances (i.e., short texts) in parenthesis. 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Experiments ranges and choices of hyperparameters. 
Unidir refers to the regular RNNs presented in Section 2.1.1, 
and bidir refers to bidirectional RNNs introduced in (Schuster 
and Paliwal, 1997). 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> All train/validation/test splits can be found at https:// github.com/Franck-Dernoncourt/naacl2016</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatic dialog act segmentation and classification in multiparty meetings</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Ang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ICASSP (1)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1061" to="1064" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A convolutional neural network for modelling sentences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Blunsom</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics. Proceedings of the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics. the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Natural language processing (almost) from scratch</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">[</forename><surname>Cho</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1409.1259.[Collobertetal.2011</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of Machine Learning Research</title>
		<editor>Ronan Collobert, Jason Weston, Léon Bottou, Michael Karlen, Koray Kavukcuoglu, and Pavel Kuksa</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2493" to="2537" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Encoderdecoder approaches. arXiv preprint</note>
	<note>On the properties of neural machine translation</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Deep learning for efficient discriminative parsing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ronan</forename><surname>Collobert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>number EPFL-CONF-192374</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">International Conference on Artificial Intelligence and Statistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">AdobeMIT submission to the DSTC 4 Spoken Language Understanding pilot task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Dernoncourt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">7th International Workshop on Spoken Dialogue Systems (IWSDS)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Long short-term memory</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Sepp Hochreiter and Jürgen Schmidhuber</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1735" to="1780" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Backoff model training using partially observed data: application to dialog act tagging</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Janin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1404.2188</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the main conference on Human Language Technology Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association of Computational Linguistics</title>
		<editor>Dan Jurafsky, Elizabeth Shriberg, and Debra Biasca</editor>
		<meeting>the main conference on Human Language Technology Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association of Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="97" to="102" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
	<note>Nal Kalchbrenner. Phil Blunsom. 2014. A convolutional neural network for modelling sentences</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">[</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>and Matthew Henderson. 2015. Dialog State Tracking Challenge 4: Handbook</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Fourth Dialog State Tracking Challenge</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">[</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 7th International Workshop on Spoken Dialogue Systems (IWSDS)</title>
		<meeting>the 7th International Workshop on Spoken Dialogue Systems (IWSDS)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Convolutional neural networks for sentence classification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoon</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1746" to="1751" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Token-based chunking of turninternal dialogue act sequences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">[</forename><surname>Lendvai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeroen</forename><surname>Geertzen2007] Piroska Lendvai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Geertzen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 8th SIGDIAL Workshop on Discourse and Dialogue</title>
		<meeting>the 8th SIGDIAL Workshop on Discourse and Dialogue</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="174" to="181" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Rnnlm-recurrent neural network language modeling toolkit</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">[</forename><surname>Mikolov</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the 2011 ASRU Workshop</title>
		<meeting>of the 2011 ASRU Workshop</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011-01" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="196" to="201" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Efficient estimation of word representations in vector space</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">[</forename><surname>Mikolov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1301.3781</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Distributed representations of words and phrases and their compositionality</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">[</forename><surname>Mikolov</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Advances in neural information processing systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3111" to="3119" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dependency tree-based sentiment classification using CRFs with hidden variables</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Nakagawa</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Human Language Technologies: The</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dialogue act classification using language models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeffrey</forename><surname>Pennington</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Socher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher D Manning ;</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Norbert</forename><surname>Reithinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martin</forename><surname>Klesen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Annual Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<editor>EuroSpeech. Citeseer</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1532" to="1543" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>GloVe: global vectors for word representation</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Dialog act tagging using memory-based learning. Term project</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mihai</forename><surname>Rotaru</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="255" to="276" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>University of Pittsburgh</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bidirectional recurrent neural networks. Signal Processing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paliwal1997] Mike</forename><surname>Schuster</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Schuster</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Kuldip</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Paliwal</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Transactions on</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2673" to="2681" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Shriberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Elizabeth Shriberg</title>
		<editor>Raj Dhillon, Sonali Bhagat, Jeremy Ang, and Hannah Carvey</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">From symbolic to sub-symbolic information in question classification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Silva</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2012 Joint Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing and Computational Natural Language Learning</title>
		<meeting>the 2012 Joint Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing and Computational Natural Language Learning</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1201" to="1211" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Technical report</note>
	<note>The ICSI meeting recorder dialog act (MRDA) corpus</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dialogue act modeling for automatic tagging and recognition of conversational speech</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">[</forename><surname>Stolcke</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="339" to="373" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Baselines and bigrams: Simple, good sentiment and topic classification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Manning2012] Sida</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher D</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 50th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Short Papers</title>
		<meeting>the 50th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Short Papers</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="90" to="94" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Matthew D Zeiler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1212.5701</idno>
		<title level="m">Adadelta: An adaptive learning rate method</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
